ADRIANA DIPIETRO

New York, NY 11788 | 631-902-5188 | adrianadipietro4@gmail.com Github | Blog | LinkedIn

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Full-stack web developer experienced in Object Oriented Programming. With a background in writing and communications, I prioritize succinct communication resulting in positive collaboration and effective teamwork. As I am **actively and quickly learning** new technologies and operating systems, I bring the ability to adapt to the workplace and the technology industry.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript (ES6), ReactJS, Redux, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Sinatra, PostgreSQL, SQL, Firebase Windows, Mac OS X, Visual Studio, Google Apps, Git, ActiveRecord, jQuery, Webpack, Node Package Manager

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

UPFRONT - Github

SPA resource for maintaining and updating a to-do list for organizing tasks by status and/or category.

- Developed a Ruby on Rails backend and a JavaScript frontend application.
- Implemented CRUD functionality and a friendly UI.
- Created an API for data storage and manipulation.

CIRCE - Github

A virtual application for users to create, store and share artistic content, i.e. artwork, essays, videos. (This project is currently being maintained)

- Developing a Ruby on Rails backend and a JavaScript frontend application.
- Utilizing React library to build an interactive UI. Utilizing Redux to maintain state and persist data.

SILVERMARK - Github

A bookmark management system for users to create and store favored websites amongst browsers.

- Developed a Ruby on Rails backend API.
- Implemented CRUD functionality while persisting data.

EDUCATION

Flatiron School Online Program
Full Stack Web Development Program 09/2020 - 09/2021

Siena College Bachelor of Art in English Literature Loudonville, NY Graduated May 2019

EXPERIENCE

Suffolk County Human Rights Commission

Research Intern

Hauppauge, NY 06/2019 - 08/2019

- Researched legislature relating to discrimination and equality of protected categories, et. al The Human Rights Law, Title VII of the Civil Rights Act...
- Assisted senior investigators in gathering information on Complainant(s), Respondent(s), witnesses, and companies to prepare written reports for cases under the jurisdiction of the New York Division of Human Rights.

Siena College Marketing & Communications

Loudonville, NY 09/2018 - 05/2019

Writing & Communications Intern

- Updated and maintained Siena College's LinkedIn, MeritPages, Facebook account(s).
- Prepared and published articles on Siena College's website and e-Newsletter increasing potential applicants by 10%.